在正义方面，古波斯帝国可以说是严酷而公正的。
In terms of justice, the ancient Persian Empire could be said to have been harsh, but fair.
它的法典中包含“lex talionis”的准则，表示以眼还眼，以牙
The criminal code included the principal of “lex talionis”, an eye for an eye, tooth
还牙，轻者通常会处以罚款，还可能被冠以诽谤的烙印，
for a tooth, misdemeanors usually warranted fines, you might be branded for slander,
而对于严厉的罪行，将会被处以死刑。
and for the worst crimes you would get the death penalty.
死刑有“两振出局”的规则，这意味着某人不会因为初犯
On occasions there was a two strikes rule, meaning someone wouldn’t be executed for
而被处死。
their first offense.
所以，在古波斯，两次重罪就要见上帝。
So, there you are in ancient Persia, two strikes down.
你想知道死刑如何会被判罚。
You are wondering how the death penalty will be metered out.
是有可能被灰烬窒息？或是把熔化的黄金倾注到受刑者的喉咙
Will it be suffocation by ashes perhaps, or maybe having molten gold poured down your
就像罗马皇帝瓦勒良（传言俘虏后被波斯人倾注黄金致死）可能经历的那样。
throat as what might have happened to the Roman emperor Valerian.
很难说那个更糟，但是今天我们认为有一种波斯的刑罚措施
It’s hard to say which would be worse, but today we think have a Persian punishment that
是其中最为残酷的。
was the most brutal of them all.
虽然古波斯人确实有严格的关于正义的法律，
While the ancient Persians did have strict laws pertaining to matters of justice,
但如同我们要讲的，这不能总是阻止他们变得异常残忍。
as we said, that didn’t at times stop them from being tremendously brutal.
在讨论最严重的刑罚之前，我们会再举几个
We’ll give you a few more examples before we get to possibly the worst punishment of
例子。
them all.
这有一位古波斯法官锡桑内斯（Sisamnes）处死的故事。
Take for example the death of a Persian judge called Sisamnes.
据说他很贪腐，公元前530年至公元前522年在位的波斯国王，冈比西斯二世
It’s said that he was corrupt and King Cambyses II of Persia who ruled from 530 BC to 522
想要以他为事例，警告那些其他想要
BC wanted to make an example out of him as a warning to others who might think about
腐蚀法庭的人。
corrupting the courts.
据说该法官从头到脚被剥皮，然后用他的外皮做了
It’s said the judge was flayed from head to toe and then his skin was used to make
一把椅子。
a chair.
正如故事所说，之后任何被任命为法官的人都必须在那张椅子上
As the tale goes, anyone appointed from then on as a judge would have to spend some time
坐上一段时间，这样他们就会了解如果自己贪腐的下场。
sitting in that chair so they would know what would happen if they were corrupt.
你可以在“The Arrest of Sisamnes”和“Flaying of Sisamnes”
You can see this horrific spectacle in the paintings “The Arrest of Sisamnes” and
两幅画作中看到这种可怕的场景。
“Flaying of Sisamnes.”
然后就是居鲁士大帝（Cyrus the Great）的故事。
Then there’s the story of Cyrus the Great.
据记载，他的妻子对她的一位太监感到非常不满。
It’s written that his wife became quite unhappy with one of her eunuchs.
事实上她很不高兴，并下令将他杀死3次。
So unhappy in fact, that she ordered that he be killed three times.
这被称为三重死亡。
This is called The Triple Death.
首先他的眼睛被挖掉，然后被看护了到健康状态。
It’s said first his eyes were pulled from his head, but then he was nursed back to health.
第二次死亡是被剥皮，但是他又得到了护理，所以也没有死。
His second death was being flayed, but again he was nursed so he wouldn’t die.
当然我们认为他没有被完全剥皮，因为那只会导致死亡。
We imagine he couldn’t have been completely flayed as that resulted in certain death.
当他好一些时，会被钉在十字架上处死，这样执行就完成了。
When he was better he was then crucified and the job was done.
然而，我们会说这个故事有很多版本。
We should say, however, that there are many versions of this tale.
但现在我们将坚持使用上述的版本。
We’ll stick with this one for now.
那么，考虑到上述的两次处决，还会有更惨的故事发生吗？
So, with these two executions in mind, could there really be anything worse?
好吧，现在我们必须要看一个叫做米特拉达梯（Mithridates）的男人的故事。
Well, now we have to look at the story of a man called Mithridates.
他是一个年轻的波斯士兵，于公元前401年被处死。
He was a young Persian soldier who was put to death in 401BC.
据说这个人意外杀死了谋逆的叛逆者赛勒斯（Cyrus the Younger），
It’s said this man accidentally killed Cyrus the Younger, the rebel who was intending to
他意图杀死哥哥阿尔萨斯（Arsaces），以便可以继承王位。
kill his older brother Arsaces so he could inherit the throne.
成千上万的人在追随着赛勒斯，这场战争在库纳萨战役中达到高潮。
Thousands of men were behind Cyrus and this culminated in the Battle of Cunaxa.
赛勒斯的军队在向阿尔萨斯的军队冲锋之后占据了上风，一切进展顺利，
Cyrus’ army got the upper hand after charging Artaxerxes' army, all was going well, the
王位就在他眼前。
throne was in his sights.
赛勒斯紧接着攻击了他哥哥的私人护卫，然后……哎呀……不知打哪来的
Cyrus then went to attack his brother’s personal bodyguard and then…oops…out of
标枪击中并当场杀死了他。
nowhere a javelin just hit him and killed him on the spot.
这对叛军来说是巨大的挫折，然后就全都撤退了。
This was a huge setback for the rebels and they all retreated.
他们未来的国王已经死了，一切都结束了。
Their future king was dead, it was over.
我们知道这些是因为这个故事是由希腊传记作家普鲁塔克（Plutarch）在他的
We know this because the story was recorded by the Greek biographer Plutarch in his essay
撰文中记录的叫做“阿尔萨斯的一生”。
the “Life of Artaxerxes.”
另一位名叫希提亚斯（Ctesias）的希腊作家告诉普鲁塔克了那个用标枪意外
Another Greek writer called Ctesias told Plutarch of the fate of the man that accidentally killed
杀死塞勒斯的人的命运。
Cyrus with that javelin.
如你所知，他的名字叫米特拉达梯。
As you know, his name was Mithridates.
可以理解的是也许有些人对米特拉达梯感到些许恼火，
It’s understandable perhaps that some people were perhaps a bit miffed with Mithridates.
只有最严厉的惩罚才能奏效，这就是船刑的由来。
Only the severest of punishments would do, and that’s where scaphism comes in.
普鲁塔克是这样描述这种非常不寻常的极刑的。
This is how Plutarch describes this very unusual kind of death penalty.
由于他的语言有些过时，我们会予以改述。
We will paraphrase as his language is a bit dated now.
将两艘大小相等的船上下叠放并钉死。
So, two boats of equal size were put on top of each other and nailed together.
有点像一个浮动的棺材。
It kind of made a floating coffin.
在船上打洞，以便囚犯可以被固定在船上，但同时
Holes were made in the boats so that the prisoner could be fastened in the them but with his
双手，双脚和头部要漏出来。
hands, feet and head sticking out.
要目前为止还算平常。
So far so good.
他在漂浮，头向外伸出，身体也越来越热。
He was floating, his head was protruding, he was getting rather hot.
炽热的光线灼烧着他的脸。
He was left there with the hot sun shining on his face.
身体也在漂浮的坟墓中烤的滚烫。
His body was baking hot inside the floating tomb.
然后，他们会强制给米特拉达梯适量的喂食牛奶和蜂蜜，
They then force fed Mithridates milk and honey, and in good size portions, too.
并把食物涂抹到他的脸上。
They also covered his face with the stuff.
很快，他被蜂蜜覆盖的脸则被苍蝇铺满，苍蝇以他的脸部为餐桌大肆的进食着。
Soon his honey-covered face was covered with flies that were feasting on him and the honey.
然后，米特拉达梯被强制吃的越来越多，直到他的胸腹张开并且产生了
He was then force fed more and more until his belly was distended and he had produced
大量的排泄物。
quite the pile of excrement.
此时的景象如普鲁塔克所说，“蠕动的蛆虫
At this point, as Plutarch said, “creeping things and vermin spring out of the corruption
在腐烂的排泄物中滋生。”
and rottenness of the excrement.”
这些东西进入了米特拉达梯的肠子，而他的肉也正在从外面
These things entered Mithridates’ bowels, while his flesh was slowly being eaten too
慢慢被吃掉。
from the outside.
据说这种蠕虫的缓慢进食持续了17天。
This slow devouring by insects and vermin it’s said lasted 17 days.
到最后，可怜，年轻，标枪技术感人的米特拉达梯就这样被活生生的吃掉了。
At that point, poor, young Mithridates with the bad javelin shot was eaten alive.
十二世纪的拜占庭编年史学家乔安妮斯（Joannes）对此作了另一种描述。
There was another description of this by a 12th-century Byzantine chronicler
确实是同一故事，但她对这个故事有所修饰。
called Joannes Zonaras. It’s really the same story, but he embellished the tale somewhat.
这是逐词翻译的结论：
This is the conclusion, word for word in translation:
“被蜂蜜吸引的苍蝇，蜜蜂和黄蜂落在他的脸上和所有
“Flies, wasps, and bees, attracted by the sweetness, settle on his face and all such
裸漏在船外的部分，痛苦地折磨和刺痛这个
parts of him as project outside the boats, and miserably torment and sting
可怜的男人
the wretched man.
此外，他的胸腹因牛奶和蜂蜜的膨胀而胀开，排出液体排泄物，
Moreover his belly, distended as it is with milk and honey, throws off liquid excrements,
这些腐败滋生出各式各样的肠堆，和其围绕进食的蠕虫。
and these putrefying breed swarms of worms, intestinal and of all sorts.
受害者躺在船上，他的身躯在自己的污秽中腐烂，并被虫子吞食，
Thus the victim lying in the boats, his flesh rotting away in his own filth and devoured
一种拖延，恐怖的死法。”
by worms, dies a lingering and horrible death.”
但史上只有这一例船刑吗?
But is that it, just one case of scaphism throughout history?
好吧，看上去所有人讨论的和上述的是同一个，
Well, it seems like the one case everyone talks about is the one we just described,
尽管大多数资料都称”船刑”是一种古老的惩罚措施，就像会时常发生的
although most sources call scaphism an ancient form of punishment as if it happened time
一样。
and again.
我们确实从《基督教殉道史》一书中有所摘录。
We did find an excerpt from a book called “The History of Christian Martyrdom.”
这本书中记载了公元363年一位名叫马库斯（Marcus）的主教摧毁了一座异教寺庙，
In that book it’s written that a bishop called Marcus in 363 AD destroyed a pagan
然后建立了一座教堂。
temple and then erected a church.
罗马皇帝朱利安对此很不买账。
This didn’t go down well with Roman emperor Julian the Apostate.
书中记载作为惩罚，他把马库斯吊在一个篮子里，
It’s written that as punishment he took Marcus and hung him up in a basket and left
让他在那里被昆虫盛宴。
him there to be feasted on by insects.
但这更像是一个死在烈日下的案例，而不是硬核的船刑措施。
But this seems like a case of dying in the hot sun rather than hardcore scaphism.
事实上在“Wiki Talk“的页面上有很多关于船刑的争论，
There’s actually quite the debate about scaphism on the Wiki Talk page, with some
一些写者质疑普鲁塔克的真实性，并询问其他来源支持。
editors questioning the veracity of Plutarch and asking for other sources.
普鲁塔克确实写了关于船刑的论述，但一些历史学家认为他可能
Plutarch did indeed write that account of scaphism, but some historians believe he may
是为了妖魔化波斯人并使他自己的文化看起来更好。
have done so to demonize the Persians and make his own culture look better.
我们永远不会确切地知道普鲁塔克发生了什么，但是上述则是现在流行最广的
We will never know exactly what happened to Mithridates, but right now that’s the prevailing
船刑版本。
story.
也许他是唯一一个知道全部过程的人，也可能老普鲁塔克只是
Perhaps he was the only man ever to get the full dose of scaphism, or maybe old Plutarch
是古时期的一个虚假新闻出版商。
was an ancient publisher of fake news.
那么，我们是否找到了有史以来最恶劣的惩罚？
So, did we find the worst punishment of all time?
另外，请访问名为“I Am”的全新频道。
Also, check out the brand new channel called “I Am.”
从真实生活在其中的人们的角度讲述真实的故事。
Real stories come to life as they’re told from the perspective of the people who lived it.
立即查看“穿刺手弗拉德”，并成为第一个订阅的人之一！
Check out “I Am Vlad the Impaler” right now and be one of the first to subscribe!